<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Johnson Zhou</title><link>https://jzhou.org/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Johnson Zhou</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 20:20:43 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jzhou.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The future of Semi-pro Photography?</title><link>https://jzhou.org/2019/future-digital-camera/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 20:20:43 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhou.org/2019/future-digital-camera/</guid><description>To talk about future, the past has to pass first, here is my history.
Influenced by my dad, I have been in the camera game for a while. I am not a real photographer, but I&amp;rsquo;ve always kept a semi-professional camera around. I started from a Pentax ME Super: Pentax ME Super is a pretty good representation of the film era. Aperture priority metering, manual shutter, etc. It gave me a crash course of photography.</description></item><item><title>My Doggy GPS Tracking Solution</title><link>https://jzhou.org/2019/dog-tracking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 23:46:05 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhou.org/2019/dog-tracking/</guid><description>Existing dog trackers either don&amp;rsquo;t do real time GPS tracking or calls for an expensive subscription, here are some examples:
Whistle 3 Real-time tracking with GPS and LTE Device Cost $78.99 Monthly $9.99 or $167 for 2 years Findster Duo+ GPS tracking, only 3 mile range in open field Device Cost $149.99 No subscription needed Bartun Mini GPS Tracker Real-time tracking with GPS and SMS/2G Device Cost $45.</description></item><item><title>Hello, World!</title><link>https://jzhou.org/2019/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 21:07:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhou.org/2019/hello-world/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve finally decided to spin up another personal blog. Hopefully this one last longer&amp;hellip; It does have the latest tech. It is completely static and served over CloudFront from a S3 bucket (Yes, I still need to pay for it).
Since it is a personal blog, and me being me, this blog is gonna be totally random. There is gonna be Code, Photography, Politics, 3D Printer, Hardware&amp;hellip; I mean, hopefully there is gonna be Code, Photography, Politics, 3D Printer, Hardware&amp;hellip; I am lazy &amp;ldquo;turbulent&amp;rdquo;, according to the totally accurate 13 personalities thing, there is some possibility that this could be my last post here.</description></item></channel></rss>