<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Johnson Zhou on Johnson Zhou</title><link>https://jzhou.org/</link><description>Recent content in Johnson Zhou on Johnson Zhou</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 20:20:43 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The future of Semi-pro Photography?</title><link>https://jzhou.org/2019/future-digital-camera/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 20:20:43 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhou.org/2019/future-digital-camera/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;To talk about future, the past has to pass first, here is my history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Influenced by my dad, I have been in the camera game for a while. I am not a real photographer, but I&amp;rsquo;ve always kept a semi-professional camera around.
I started from a Pentax ME Super:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
Pentax ME Super is a pretty good representation of the film era. Aperture priority metering, manual shutter, etc. It gave me a crash course of photography.
You have to be sure of every shutter release because, unlike what people had been saying, film ain&amp;rsquo;t cheap, especially for a young kid like me.
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t really afford (or justify the cost to my parents) to have the film processed and printed, so I learnt to process black and white slides myself.
I bought a cheapo russian projector and view my processed film this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IT WAS WAY TOO HIP FOR THE MODERN DAY ME THOUGH:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_4.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_5.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I had enough of the crap about film. I was always guessing, always paying for the stupid lab&amp;hellip; so I moved to Pentax K-10D,
it was the only DSLR that I can afford on the used market (I think this was 2012, so yeah, I ain&amp;rsquo;t rich)
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
I kept my film lense for the camera, since I can&amp;rsquo;t afford to purchase a digital lens. Pentax digital cameras worked really well with their old lenses.
I was able to shoot with manual focusing and aperture priority pretty easily, even as a beginner digital photographer.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_6.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_7.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After which, I found a part-time job in my college and was able to afford the proper equipment, a Pentax K-5 with a couple of proper digital lenses.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_8.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
I owned K-5 for a while. It is a great camera and even today&amp;rsquo;s camera is not that better than it, a lot of good photos were taken with the setup.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_9.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_10.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_11.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
During the K-5 ownership I stopped to see too much of an improvement in my photos. Slowly, the &lt;strong&gt;hunt of photo op&lt;/strong&gt; becomes more of a issue than actually taking the photo properly.
K-5 and the DSLR setup&amp;rsquo;s weight became a huge problem. Heavy equipment simply makes my trip less enjoyable as an unprofessional photographer.
Taking photos is only a small part of traveling for me. So I gradually stopped taking my cameras for trips. And the camera starts to collect dust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is hope, the hope is from &lt;strong&gt;SONY&lt;/strong&gt;, my next camera is the Sony Alpha α6000
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_12.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
I don&amp;rsquo;t see much of a functional difference between the Sony and K-5, the Sony is simply lighter and smaller. Takeing it on a trip is a breeze, and the Sony sensor is simply impressive.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_13.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_14.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_15.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_23.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, quite some time has passed and then, &lt;strong&gt;I GOT A JOB!&lt;/strong&gt; The poor student is gone and I get to buy pretty much any camera I want if I try to spend some time to save. In the meantime, Pentax made the famous K-1, so I bought one.
That marks my first ever Full-frame camera.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_16.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
I also got a proper lens to go along with it, the FA 31 Limited. (Obviously I have other lenses too, this one is just too pretty)
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_17.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Full-frame cameras are just simply better than APS-C cameras because of the color rendering, low ISO noise, and beautiful bokeh. Most importantly, the separation of the object and background, even at distance.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_18.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;click to zoom for the separation effect&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_19.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_20.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, it still has the same problem as the K-5. It is simply too heavy and too bulky.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not the Sony A7 series you ask? Because even though the camera body is small, the lenses are huge and heavy, making the concept useless in my eyes.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_21.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weight and bulk kept troubling my mind during my ownership of K-1. With the improvements of smartphone cameras
I often &amp;ldquo;forget&amp;rdquo; to bring the K-1, going on a trip with just my smartphone. I sometimes would think that it would be nice if a certain photo is taken with the K-1.
But I quickly forget it because it just doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem worth it to me to bring the whole setup for this one photo op.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things can get even worse&amp;hellip; The new dual/quad camera smartphones basically make APS-C cameras useless.
I personally believe bokeh is the only advantage of a APS-C camera over a high quality smartphone and digital bokeh killed that one thing.
With a little digital processing, compression, I don&amp;rsquo;t think you can tell much of a difference&amp;hellip; For example, one of the a6000 photos is actually taken with an iPhone X&amp;hellip; Sorry I tricked you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can still argue that full frame cameras have a place in the modern days because of the low light ability, natural color rendering, and object separation.
Digital processing is still noticeable in some places, a good lens and good sensor still beat it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well there is hope for Cameras, the hope is from &lt;strong&gt;SONY&lt;/strong&gt;, again, so I sold my K-1 and got my next camera. The Sony RX1R
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_22.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
It is basically a combination of a Sony A7 with an excellent Zeiss Lens. It is very small and light, I would happily bring it on a trip and use it for the few photo ops that I would like to see in a better image quality.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_24.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_25.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_26.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THAT BEING SAID&amp;hellip; I have only used it on 1 trip since I bought it, a 7-day-long trip. Because after all, the camera is an extra thing to worry about,
an extra item to carry, something that doesn&amp;rsquo;t comfortably sit in a pocket. The camera on the smartphone is just too convenient and too addictive. Sometimes, even the need
to transfer photos from the camera to the smartphone becomes a justification for not using the camera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I would probably keep the camera, it is non intrusive enough, but it would be one of the first things I would sell if I ever need money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So&amp;hellip; what is the future then?&lt;/strong&gt; Well, There is no future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smartphone cameras will replace semi-pro digital cameras. Sorry, I wasted your time. LOL.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, seriously, I thought a compact camera with good zooming ability, like the Sony RX100VI, will become the next camera I buy. But then, Huawei made the P30 Pro with 50X Zoom&amp;hellip;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/digital_camera_27.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
So yeah, no future&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Doggy GPS Tracking Solution</title><link>https://jzhou.org/2019/dog-tracking/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 23:46:05 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhou.org/2019/dog-tracking/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Existing dog trackers either don&amp;rsquo;t do real time GPS tracking or calls for an expensive subscription, here are some examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Whistle-GPS-Tracker-Activity-Monitor/dp/B01N7MWKWY/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Whistle 3&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Real-time tracking with GPS and LTE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device Cost $78.99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Monthly $9.99 or $167 for 2 years&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Findster-Tracker-Free-Monthly-Fees/dp/B07FFCRQHN&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Findster Duo+&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GPS tracking, only 3 mile range in open field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device Cost $149.99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No subscription needed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Bartun-Waterproof-Locating-Positioning-Geo-Fence/&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bartun Mini GPS Tracker&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Real-time tracking with GPS and SMS/2G&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Device Cost $45.99&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide your own SIM Card&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one that meets my requirements, the &lt;strong&gt;Whistle 3&lt;/strong&gt;, would cost me around $78.99 + $7 per month, which is around &lt;strong&gt;$160&lt;/strong&gt; for the first year. It seems a bit too much. However, I always want to get my dog a tracker, since he has quite a bad rep about bolting. With me working, He has to stay home alone most of the day, any person can accidentally let him out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By chance, I found this: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Samsung-SmartThings-SM-V110AZWAATT-Tracker-Tracking&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Samsung SmartThings Tracker&lt;/a&gt;. It has all the feature of the Whistle 3 in terms of tracking, but cost just &lt;strong&gt;$79.99&lt;/strong&gt; for the first year and &lt;strong&gt;$50&lt;/strong&gt; for the subsequent years.
However, there isn&amp;rsquo;t an existing dog collar mount for it. Using a key ring is also out of question since Samsung managed to make the hole on the tracker very very small:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/dog_tracker_1_lite.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
I initially simply tied it to my dog&amp;rsquo;s collar with a string, but charging it became a problem since it is difficult to remove. No solution is available online so I decided to make one with my 3D printers:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://jzhou.org/images/dog_tracker_2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;
I put a cut out on the side to improve material efficiency while making easier to remove for charging. You don&amp;rsquo;t need support for the cut out since it is diamond shaped. To secure the tracker in place, I took advantage of the curved edges and made the ring hole structure intruding from the side. My dog plays quite rough and hasn&amp;rsquo;t managed to get it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thingiverse.com/thing:3481587&#34; rel=&#34;nofollow noreferrer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Thingiverse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hello, World!</title><link>https://jzhou.org/2019/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 21:07:09 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://jzhou.org/2019/hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve finally decided to spin up another personal blog. Hopefully this one last longer&amp;hellip; It does have the latest tech. It is completely static and served over CloudFront from a S3 bucket (Yes, I still need to pay for it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it is a &lt;strong&gt;personal&lt;/strong&gt; blog, and me being me, this blog is gonna be totally random. There is gonna be Code, Photography, Politics, 3D Printer, Hardware&amp;hellip; I mean, &lt;strong&gt;hopefully&lt;/strong&gt; there is gonna be Code, Photography, Politics, 3D Printer, Hardware&amp;hellip; I am lazy &amp;ldquo;turbulent&amp;rdquo;, according to the totally accurate 13 personalities thing, there is some possibility that this could be my last post here. I mean we are talking about me here.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
Peace.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>